Records of the Taller Martín Pescador Press, Juan Pascoe, Printer 1971-2014
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Records of the Taller Martín Pescador Press, Juan Pascoe, Printer 1971-2014
MS 353
Juan Pascoe
Correspondence, printing production materials, chapbooks, invitations, posters, and other materials relating to, or produced by, handpress printer Juan Pascoe. Most published monographs were catalogued and shelved separately.
2.25 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/ E-Mail: LBRY-askspcoll@email.arizona.edu
Restrictions
There are no restrictions on this collection.
Biographical Note
Juan Pascoe, handpress printer, was born in Chicago in 1946. He studied English at Whitman College, BA 1969. Pascoe spent a year as a printing apprentice to Harry Duncan at the Cummington Press in West Branch, Iowa, 1971-1972. He moved to Mexico in 1973 and first printed under Imprenta Rasucache, or “Shabby Press,” 1973-1975, before founding the Taller Martín Pescador (Kingfisher Workshop) in 1975.
In 1987, he produced the first book reflecting his historical interest in Mexican book arts (no. 112 on checklist). Pascoe has since become known for major studies of 16th and 17th century Mexican printers. He is currently located in Tacámbaro, near Mexico City.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into four series.
Series I: Biographical Information, undated
Series II: West Branch, Iowa, 1971-1972
Series III: Imprenta Rascuache, in Mexico, 1973-1975
Series IV: Taller Martín Pescador, in Mexico, 1975-ongoing
Scope and Content Note
The bulk of this collection consists of printing production materials of the handpress printer, Juan Pascoe. It is divided into four series. The bulk of the collection documents work done under the Taller Martín Pescador imprint.
Materials range from calling cards and invitations to exhibition posters; from chapbooks of avant-garde poetry to folio-sized historical studies and biographies of Mexican printers of the 16th-18th centuries. Writers and illustrators whose work first became known through publication at the Taller Martín Pescador have since become established as major figures.
Mainly in Spanish, with some English language materials. The number preceding the work corresponds with Mr. Pascoe’s numbering of his productions. Gaps in the sequence indicate titles that were catalogued separately, found later in the guide in Oversized Materials, or, in some cases, titles the archive lacks.
Pascoe, Juan 1946—.; Cummington Press –Iowa –United States.; Imprenta Rascuache –Mexico City –Mexico.; Taller Martin Pescador –Mexico City –Mexico.; Printers – Mexico.; Small presses – Mexico – 20th Century.; Artists’ books – Mexico.; Mexico – Mexico City.; West Branch –Iowa –United States.; Printmakers – Mexican
Container List
- Records of the Taller Martín Pescador Press, 1971-1998; Series I
  - Biographical information, 1981-- (Box 1, Folder 1)
- West Branch, Iowa, 1971-1972; Series II
  - Del Resto, aunque nueftro eftilo no fea tan elegante, y cafto…, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 1)
  - The True Collected Works of Jorge Luis Borges, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 3)
  - The Creation of Angels, Leopoldo Lugones, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 5)
  - “Come to See the Sun Dance” theater program, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 6)
  - Esta peoma, denominado Soneto contra los románticos…, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 7)
  - “As You Like It” theater program, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 8)
  - “The White Angel” theater program, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 9)
  - “A Summer Workshop in the Arts” informative flyer, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 2, Item 10)
- Imprenta Rascuache, 1973-1975; Series III
  - Proof sheet of cover for Migajas, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 13a)
  - Origenes del Venado que es también el muchacho Hatsikan…, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 14)
  - Muestrario. Sheet of type examples from Imprenta Rascuache, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 15)
  - Poster for Siglo XXI Editores, S.A. – see Oversized Materials, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 16)
  - Una cancion anonima Española del siglo XV…, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 18)
  - Para celebrar el 1er cumpleaños de Ivan Perez…, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 19)
  - “Por si las Moscas,” romance historico que compuso A. Rubalcava, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 20)
  - Invitation to the presentation of Yo, el supremo by A. Roa Bastos, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 21)
  - Carla Rippey Wright expone sus serigrafias, aguafuertes, y…, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 22)
  - Jardinillo Espiritual. Canciones and Decires Compuestos…, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 25)
  - Invitation to the wedding of Anita Plumb and Jeremy Harmer, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 3, Item 26)
- Taller Martín Pescador, in Mexico, 1975-ongoing; Series IV
  - El Taller Martín Pescador anuncia la publication de Eolicas…, undated (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 271)
  - El 1 de Agosto de 1976 empezará a circular bimestralmente La Sirena…, undated (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 28)
  - El dia quince de junio… Birth announcement for H. P. Wurfl, undated (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 29)
  - Un Nuevo libro por José Antonio Montero, Cepo de Plumas…, undated (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 32a)
  - Ediciones limitadas de Poesia Impresas a Mano…, undated (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 36)
  - Taller Martín Pescador public su primer libro, Eólicas, por…, undated (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 37)
  - La Rama version del Puerto de la Villa Rica de la Vera Cruz…, undated (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 39)
  - Queda usted cordialmente invitado una exposicion de Pinturas,…, undated (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 42)
  - El Institutio Anglo-Mexicano de Cultura presenta…Carla Rippey..., undated (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 43)
  - Se les invita a la presentación del libro La Sibila de Cumas…, undated (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 44a)
  - Se les invita a la presentación del libro Dos Extremos… (red), undated (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 45a)
  - Se les invita a la presentación del libro Dos Estremos… (gray), undated (Box 1, Folder 4, Item 45b)
  - Quirino Montalvo Corro, Fabricante de Jarnas y Requintos…, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 48)
  - Efraín Huerta 50 Poeminimos, Taller Martín Pescador…, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 50a)
  - Presentación invitacion, Carmen Boullosa…La Memoria Vacia…, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 51a)
  - Este portafolio contiene un grabado de Felipe Ehrenberg…, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 52)
  - Cuaderno del nómada: Tomás Segovia…, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 53a)
  - Ticket for Cuaderno del nómada, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 53b)
  - Announcement for Cuaderno del nómada, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 53c)
  - Este ejemplar de MAINS poema de Víctor Serge..., 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 54a)
  - Invitation to Mains/Manos, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 54b)
  - Announcement for Mains/Manos, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 54c)
  - Este portafolio contiene un grabado…Carla Rippey…, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 56)
  - “Memoria,” Derechos reservasos MCMLXXVIII por Elsa Cross, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 57)
  - Este portafolio contiene un grabado…Carla Rippey…, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 59)
  - “Poema,” por Coral Bracho, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 60)
  - Este portafolio contiene un grabado…Lucrecia Gargollo…, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 61)
  - Un Nuevo libro de Octavio Paz y Charles Tomlinson “Air Born”…, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 63b)
  - Se les invita a la presentación del libro Air Born…, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 63c)
  - Air Born, hijos del Aire Octavio Paz y Charles Tomlinson…, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 63d)
  - Taller Martín Pescador les invita…Cinco Plaquettes…, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 70)
  - Este portafolio contiene un grabado…Carla Rippey…, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 5, Item 71)
  - “Coplas de Adivinanza” por Arcadio Hidalgo…, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 72)
  - “Un cuneto de la tradición oral veracruzana” en la Version de…, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 74)
  - Oleos, Dibujos y Grabados…Dionisio Pascoe, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 76)
  - Publication announcement for La versada, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 77a)
  - Los invitación a… “Tres Libros y una Mesa Redonda”, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 82)
  - Aveces de mi fortuna en una trise inclemencia con los rayos…, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 84)
  - A Fabienne. Farewell y otros poemas, Adolfo Castañón, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 85)
  - “Two Pagan Monologues” by Harry Duncan, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 6, Item 86)
  - Pascoe family Christmas card. Engraving, V. Dutertre. (2 copies), 1982-1988 (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 89)
  - El Incio. Poemas de Verónica Volkow. Intended book spine, 1982-1988 (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 90a)
  - “Two Pagan Monologues” by Harry Duncan, 1982-1988 (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 91)
  - El Grupo Mono Blanco, Teatro el Cuervo… (crème), 1982-1988 (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 94)
  - El Grupo Mono Blanco, Teatro el Cuervo… (yellow), 1982-1988 (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 94a)
  - Para el mar tormentoso… poema de José Luis Rivas. (2 copies), 1982-1988 (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 97)
  - El 27 de noviembre…Trama Lana (Obrajería de Tacámbaro)…, 1982-1988 (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 102)
  - A las 7 pm del…Roman Zavala Cervantes, birth announcement, 1982-1988 (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 104)
  - Una feliz Navidad. Illustration by Dutertre, 1982-1988 (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 105)
  - Invitation. “La Salvaja,’ poemas de Carmen Boullosa, 1982-1988 (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 106a)
  - Announcement. Del Segundo convent de esta provincial…, 1982-1988 (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 107a)
  - Invitation to the presentation of Cuerpos, 1982-1988 (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 108a)
  - Doctrinalis Fidei in Michuacanensium Indorum Linguam…, 1982-1988 (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 110)
  - Baptismal announcement for Oyuki Moriya, 1982-1988 (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 112)
  - Primer texto conocido de la tipografía novohispana…, 1982-1988 (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 113)
  - Día de Santa Rosa, MCMLXXXIX, 1982-1988 (Box 1, Folder 7, Item 116)
  - Coplas de El Pájaro Carpintero por Gilberto Guitiérrez Silva, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 8, Item 119b)
  - Los Dos Espedientes del Ramo Yndios…, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 8, Item 120)
  - Hans Lenz, “Reflexiones Forestales,”, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 8, Item 121)
  - Obras impresas cuya tipografía fue heche en el Taller Martín…, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 8, Item 125)
  - “Mazorca,” Francisco Segovia. Taller Martín Pescador. (2 copies), 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 8, Item 126)
  - La Persecución. Poema y Alejandro Aura. Grabados y Juan…, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 8, Item 127)
  - Invitación…La Persecución carpeta y Libro-Objeto … (2 copies), 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 8, Item 127a)
  - La Inaccesible. By Alberto Ruy Sánchez, edición de Jorge…, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 8, Item 128)
  - “Decima,” Gilberto Gutiérrez, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 8, Item 129)
  - Lourdes y Taurino. Wedding invitation, 1991-1994 (Box 1, Folder 9, Item 130)
  - Dionisio Pascoe, Pinturas. Galería del Centro Suchipilli…, 1991-1994 (Box 1, Folder 9, Item 131)
  - Death announcement. Donald Ralph Acker, 1991-1994 (Box 1, Folder 9, Item 132)
  - Cornelio Adrián César, impressor en la Nueva España…(crème), 1991-1994 (Box 1, Folder 9, Item 133a)
  - Publication announcement for Cornelio Adrián César in envelope, 1991-1994 (Box 1, Folder 9, Item 133c)
  - Envelope for Cornelio Adrián César invitation, 1991-1994 (Box 1, Folder 9, Item 133d)
  - Coplas, cantadas en distintas por Gilberto Gutiérrez, 1991-1994 (Box 1, Folder 9, Item 134)
  - New Year’s card for Grupo Mono Blondo. (2 copies), 1991-1994 (Box 1, Folder 9, Item 139)
  - “Requiescat in pace, Luis Donaldo Colosio Murrieta”, 1991-1994 (Box 1, Folder 9, Item 145)
  - Dionisio Pascoe. Una exposición Óleos, Acuarelas, Montipos…, 1991-1994 (Box 1, Folder 9, Item 148)
  - Envelope for Dionisio Pascoe, 1991-1994 (Box 1, Folder 9, Item 148)
  - Dionisio Pascoe, Obra al Pastel, Óleo, Acuarela… (2 copies), 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 10, Item 152)
  - “Centetl quauhtla maçatl centlapal yxcueponqui catca…”, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 10, Item 154)
  - Invitación…La obra de Encio Martínez. Envelope included, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 10, Item 155a)
  - Juan Pascoe. La Obra de Enrico Martinez. Taller Martín Pescador, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 10, Item 155c)
  - Pía Elizondo Fotografía. Business card, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 10, Item 156)
  - Alternate cover version of [157], 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 10, Item 157a)
  - Dionisio Pascoe, exhibition by The Carefree Gallery. (2 copies), 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 10, Item 157)
  - Eugenia Huerta. Letterhead for Eugenia Huerta, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 10, Item 159)
  - Stationary. Taller Martín Pescador. México, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 11, Item 162)
  - Dionisio Pascoe. Leonardo de Vinci 101, Mixcoac, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 11, Item 163)
  - “Briznas,” poemas de Alfonso d’Aquino, illustrados … (3 copies), 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 11, Item 164a)
  - Acto de clasura de la generación Laura Medina Frausto…, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 11, Item 165)
  - Final version of “Monodies” by Harry Duncan. (red illustration, 3copies), 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 11, Item 166)
  - Final version of “Monodies” by Harry Duncan. (blue illustration), 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 11, Item 166)
  - Marriage announcement for Anastasio and Elitania, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 11, Item 171)
  - Marriage announcement for Anastasio and Elitania (Biblos Gvarro), 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 11, Item 171a)
  - Invitation to 15th birthday party for Blanca Rosa, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 11, Item 172)
  - Después de la ceremonia religiosa….en el Salón los Pinos, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 11, Item 172a)
  - Un viaje hacia el norte. En el año de 1691…, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 12, Item 173)
  - Wedding invitation, Soledad Labaca Gonnet and Luciano Pascoe Rippey, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 12, Item 175)
  - Envelope for Gonnet-Rippey wedding invitation, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 12, Item 175)
  - El año pasado…XLVII Fabulas de Esopo…en Nahuatl y en Español, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 12, Item 178)
  - Camerino Utera Luna, 1997. Ticket label, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 12, Item 180b)
  - Discurso del Jefe de Gobierno de la Cuidad de México…, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 12, Item 181)
  - “Epirafio sobre ninguna piedra,” Octavio Paz, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 12, Item 182)
  - Pre-publication announcement for Sermon fvnebre, Oaxaca. (3 copies), 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 12, Item 183)
  - Death announcement. Elisa Pascoe de Perez, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 12, Item 185)
  - Wedding invitation. Martin Urbina and Rosalba Hernandez, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 12, Item 186)
  - Generación Eugenio Contreras Suárez, 1996-1999 (Box 1, Folder 12, Item 187)
  - Wedding, Anna Herron More y Artemio Rodriguez Cornejo, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 12, Item 188)
  - Second wedding announcement, More y Cornejo, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 12, Item 188a)
  - Se le invita una exposición…Luciernagas…, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 12, Item 191)
  - El Corazon. Un grabado en linóleo de Artemio Rodríguez…, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 12, Item 192)
  - La Loteria, cien grabados de Artemio Rodríguez…, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 12, Item 193)
  - Announcements for Fascimil del Sermon fvnebre, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 12, Item 194)
  - Grupo Mono Blanco. Memorial announcement, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 12, Item 195)
  - Inauguracion de las Nuevas Instalaciones de la Escuela…, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 12, Item 197)
  - Se le invita una exposición…Luciernagas…, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 1, Item 200)
  - Ricardo Pascoe Pierce, “Política, Moral e Instituciones para…”, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 1, Item 202)
  - Wedding invitation. Maria Cristina y Luis, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 1, Item 204)
  - Tomás Sergovia, “Otra Juventud”, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 1, Item 209)
  - Wedding announcement card. Illustration on front. No text, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 1, Item 210)
  - Wedding announcement. Marcela y Cirilo, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 1, Item 211)
  - Invitacion Escuela Secundaria Tecnica, No. 125, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 225)
  - Wedding announcement. Josefina y Jose Juan, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 226)
  - Generación, 1997-2000 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 227)
  - Célida Díz Tejeda y Bruno Olvera Zarcon…Valeria, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 228)
  - La Casa de España. El Colegio de Mexico. Catálogo histórico, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 229)
  - El Fandango de Santa Rosa, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 230)
  - Ventolera invitation, including original envelope, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 2, Item 231)
  - 50th Anniversary, Chalke Kelsall y Pascoe y Strozzi. 2 tickets, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 242)
  - 50th Anniversary. Kelsall y Strozzi, invitation and envelope, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 242)
  - William Shakespeare, Sonnet CXVI for Duncan-Garner wedding, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 244)
  - 62nd Anniversary. Las Joyas, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 245)
  - Niñas, Niños, y Padres. Erica Diaz Jacobo. Publication flyer, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 246)
  - Niñas, Niños, y Padres. Erica Diaz Jacobo. Card announcement, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 246)
  - Generación, celebration anniversary announcement, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 247)
  - Invitacion. Escuela Secundario Tecnica, No. 125, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 247a)
  - Achikoli and Temilo. Five linoleum cuts by Artemio Rodríguez, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 248)
  - Gilberto Gutiérrez y César Castro terminaron de construir…, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 249)
  - Se hizo esta jarana bajo la dirección de César Castro… (2 copies), 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 250)
  - Hecha en 2001 por César Castro en el taller de Grnpo Mono…, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 251)
  - Fandango de Santa Rosa, 1 de septiembre de 2 mil 1, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 252)
  - Fray Diego de Basalengque, Tacambaro en 1644. Reimpreso…, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 256)
  - Tardeada con el Grupo Mono Blanco en Santa Rosa, November 25, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 257a)
  - Escuela Secundario Técnica 125 Generatión, 1977-2000. Card, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 257)
  - Fandango en celebración de los veinticinco años del Grupo Mono..., 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 261)
  - Simon Duncan Garner birth announcement. (2 copies), 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 262a)
  - Jose Elian Urbina Hernandez y Candido Mora Urbina, dos años, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 262b)
  - Hernandez y Urbina, dos años. Alternate printing, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 262c)
  - Compuesto e impreso en Santa Rosa, misma hacienda en la cual…, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 262d)
  - Simon Duncan Garner birth announcement. Alternate printing, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 262e)
  - Simon Duncan Garner birth announcement. Alternate blue printing, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 3, Item 263)
  - Printing plate. Giblerto Gutiérrez hizo esta jarana para Gisela…, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 283a)
  - Printing plate. Gilberto Gutiérrez hizo esta jarana para Jesús…, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 283b)
  - Book spine. Poemas, Tomas Segovia. Ediciones sin Nombre, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 284a)
  - Printing plate. Tomás Segovia, Poemas, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 284b)
  - Printing plate. Martín Urbina Suárez, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 285a)
  - Printing plate. Tomás Urbina Suárez, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 285b)
  - Printing plate. Jesús Ramírez Ortiz, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 285c)
  - Printing plate. Juan Pascoe, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 285d)
  - Printing plate. Ex libris Andrés Henestrosa. Red rabbit illustration, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 286a)
  - Printing plate. Ex libris Andrés Henestrosa. Monument illustration, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 286b)
  - Printing plate. Ex libris Andrés Henestrosa. Curved box design, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 286c)
  - Printing plate. Ex libris Andrés Henestrosa. Vines around name, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 286d)
  - Printing plate. Ex libris Andrés Henestrosa. Pointed box design, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 286e)
  - Printing plate. Ex libris Andrés Henestrosa. Small red leaf, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 286e)
  - Ellen Eltinge Lauck Doritee de González death announcement, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 287)
  - La Versada de Arcadio Hidalgo announcement, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 288)
  - Stationary. María Isabel Grañén Porrúa, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 289a)
  - Stationary. Alfredo Harp Helú, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 289b)
  - Stationary. Alfredo Harp Helú y María Isabel Grañén Porrúa, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 289c)
  - Stationary. Helú, Porrúa, y Santiago Harp Grañén, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 289d)
  - Card. Felicidades hoy en tu dia. 10 de mayo de 2004, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 292)
  - Lourdes y Tomas wedding announcement, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 293)
  - Capilla de Nuestra Señora de Guadalupe. Las Joyas Altas…, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 294)
  - Joyce Campbell, death announcement, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 295)
  - Karina Jacobo Hurtado birth announcement, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 296)
  - Casa de la Primera Imprenta de América announcement, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 298)
  - Guy Oliver Duncan read this poem Quietude by Pablo Neruda…, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 299)
  - Poema Al Sol by Homero Aridjis, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 300)
  - Card for Jose Elian, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 301)
  - Printing plate. Ex libris Alejandro González Durán Fernández, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 302)
  - Nací el 1 de abril del 2005 Frida Melissa y mi bautizo es el dia…, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 304)
  - Carlos Pellicer, Tres Sonetos á Frida Kahlo, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 305)
  - Iranpa Instrumentos Artesanales de Cuerda business card, Estrada, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 306)
  - Juan Pascoe and Dorothy Pierce 60th anniversary card. Color photographs, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 307)
  - Grupo Gaban y Amigos. Turin, Italia, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 308)
  - Business card. Heriberto Vargas Jacobo, Abogado, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 309)
  - Printing plate. María Isabel Grañén Porrúa in illustrative design, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 312)
  - Memoria de la Gente que en el pueblo de San Geronimo…., 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 313)
  - Libros y Lectores en Mexico. Un Enlace Imperfecto, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 314)
  - Printing plate. Santiago Pascoe Strozzi in illustrative vine design, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 315)
  - Décimas de los instrumentos, Giblerto Gutiérrez Silva. Red printing, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 318)
  - Invitation. Leyendas del cerro de mariana… Red printing, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 320)
  - El Pájaro Carpintero 2006 Ramón Gutiérrez Hernádez, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 321a)
  - El Pájaro Carpintero 2010 Ramón Gutiérrez Hernádez, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 321b)
  - Printing plate. Gilberto hizo esta jarana para José Elián…, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 322)
  - Printing plate. Ex libris Matthew Duncan, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 4, Item 327)
  - Jose Elian cumpió los 6 años el 22 de marzo de 2006… (Box 2, Folder 5, Item 323)
  - Graduation information. Escuela Secundaria Tecnica 125, 2006-2007 (Box 2, Folder 5, Item 326)
  - José Rubén romero. Tacámbraro. Grabados de Artemio…, 2006-2007 (Box 2, Folder 5, Item 328)
  - Illustrated business card for G. Gutiérrez y J. R. Ortiz, 2006-2007 (Box 2, Folder 5, Item 329)
  - Business card. Heriberto Vargas Jacob, Abogado. Logo top right, 2006-2007 (Box 2, Folder 5, Item 330a)